Stanislaw M. Ulam Papers 1916-1984 Mss.Ms.Coll.54
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Professional correspondence, 1932-1986, 15.5 Linear feet 33 boxes
  - Martinez, Hugo, 1975 (Box Series I-17)
  - Martwick, Richard J., 1972 (Box Series I-17)
  - Marty, Roger H., 1968 (Box Series I-17)
  - Maruyama, Magoroh, 1971; 1976 (Box Series I-17)
    Pineapple photos
  - Maschler, Michael, 1962 (Box Series I-18)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Applied MathematicsCommittee., 1978 (Box Series I-18)
    Toscano, Nancy
  - Massera, Jose Luis, 1982 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mate, Atilla (Box Series I-18)
    See Bebernes, Jerrold
  - Mathematical Reviews, 1956-1959; 1971 (Box Series I-18)
    Crittenden, R. J.
    Gould, Stephen H.
    Wehausen, J. V.
  - Mather, Kirtley F., 1958 (Box Series I-18)
  - Matheson, L. A., 1969 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mathews, M. M., 1968 (Box Series I-18)
  - Matthias, Bernd T., 1963; n.d. (Box Series I-18)
  - Mattson, H. F., Jr., 1983 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mauldin, Daniel (Box Series I-18)
    - Folder #1, 1974-1983 (Box Series I-18)
      Scottish Book
    - Folders #2-3, n.d. (Box Series I-18)
      -See also Ser. I, Oxtoby, John C.
  - Maxwell, Philip, 1966 (Box Series I-18)
  - Maxwell, I. Robert, 1957-1983 (Box Series I-18)
    von Neumann, etc.
    -See also Ser.I, Pergamon Press, Inc.
  - May, Kenneth O., 1976 (Box Series I-18)
  - Maybee, John S., 1968-1970 (Box Series I-18)
    Norton
    U. of Colorado
  - Mayer, Maria Goeppert, 1963 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mayers, Dan E., 1969 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mayhew, Leon, 1978 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mayne, A. J., 1956 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mazur, Stanislaw, 1958-1974; n.d. (Box Series I-18)
  - McAlpin, John, 1969 (Box Series I-18)
  - McArthur, Charles W., 1969; 1974 (Box Series I-18)
  - McCarthy, John, 1957; 1980 (Box Series I-18)
  - McCarthy, Joseph L., 1974 (Box Series I-18)
    Klee, Victor
  - McClay, Douglas, n.d. (Box Series I-18)
  - McDaniel, Boyce D., 1975 (Box Series I-18)
  - McEliece, Robert J., 1977 (Box Series I-18)
  - McFarland, Marvin W., 1973 (Box Series I-18)
  - McGovern, Lane, 1947 (Box Series I-18)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1953-1966 (Box Series I-18)
    Handsfield, Hugh W.
    Oviatt, Charles D.
    Rosenbaum, Robert A.
    Salveson, Melvin E.
    Zeldin, Richard
  - McKelvey, Robert, 1967-1971 (Box Series I-18)
  - McKenzie, Ralph, 1974-1975 (Box Series I-18)
  - McMahon, Thomas, 1973-1974 (Box Series I-18)
  - McMillan, Brockway, 1958 (Box Series I-18)
    -See also Ser.I, Garabedian, Paul R.
  - McMillan, Edwin M., 1964-1972 (Box Series I-18)
    Primes
  - McPhee, Will, 1977 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mead, David G., 1977-1978 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mechem, E. L., 1963 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mehra, Jagdish, 1973-1974 (Box Series I-18)
  - Meisels, Adam, 1944 (Box Series I-18)
    Poland in WWII
  - Meisters, Gary, 1966-1982 (Box Series I-18)
  - Melzak, Z. A[lex], 1957-1973; n.d. (Box Series I-18)
    -See alsoSer.I, Sponge, John
  - Mendez, Celestino G., 1968-1981 (Box Series I-18)
  - Menger, Karl, 1939; 1945; n.d. (Box Series I-18)
  - Menzel, Donald H., 1973-1976 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mercer, G. E., 1971 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mercer, T. M. Kodwo, 1971 (Box Series I-18)
  - Metcalf, David, 1967-1982; n.d. (Box Series I-18)
    Austin, James
    Weiner, Norman
  - Metropolis, Nicholas (Box Series I-18)
    Interesting
    - Folder #1, 1949-1981 (Box Series I-18)
      Argo, Harold V.
      Smiley, Irene T.
      -See also Ser.I, Kerr, Donald M.
      -See also Ser.XIII. International Research Conference on the History of Computing (ref. letter 22.XI.1976)
    - Folders #2-4, n.d. (Box Series I-18)
  - Metropolis, Pat (Mrs. Nicholas), 1976 (Box Series I-18)
  - Metzger, Donald A., 1951 (Box Series I-18)
    LASL security
  - Meyer, Gerard G. L., 1976 (Box Series I-18)
  - Meyer, Herbert A., 1954; 1956 (Box Series I-18)
    Abstract
  - Meyer, James W., 1966 (Box Series I-18)
  - Meyer, William H., 1979 (Box Series I-18)
  - Michael, Ernest A., 1970 (Box Series I-18)
  - Michalik, Martha B., 1978 (Box Series I-18)
  - Michalski, R. S., 1983 (Box Series I-18)
  - Michelmore, Peter, 1968 (Box Series I-18)
  - Miles, James S., 1976 (Box Series I-18)
  - Miller, Clair E., 1949 (Box Series I-18)
  - Miller, Julia A. Hibbler, 1980 (Box Series I-18)
    -See also Ser.I, Shearer, Lloyd
  - Miller, Richard, 1977 (Box Series I-18)
  - Millsaps, Knox, 1977-1983; n.d. (Box Series I-18)
    -See alsoSer.I, Bednarek, A[l]
  - Mingarelli, A. B., 1982 (Box Series I-18)
  - Minguillon, Mark, 1980 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mintz, Donald J., 1972 (Box Series I-18)
  - Misner, W. K., 1969 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mitchell, D., 1965 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mitchell, James M., 1955 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mitchell, L. C., 1966; 1973 (Box Series I-18)
    Smale incident
  - Mitchell, Maurice B., 1967 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mitter, H., 1979 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mizrahi, Françoise, 1964 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mizrahi, Jacques A., 1965 (Box Series I-18)
  - Mode, Charles J., 1969 (Box Series I-19)
  - Moise, E., 1958 (Box Series I-19)
  - Moishezen, Boris (Box Series I-19)
    -See Ser.I, Chudnovsky, David
  - Mokrzyeki, Gustow A., 1977 (Box Series I-19)
  - Monard, Daniel, 1969 (Box Series I-19)
  - Monk, Donald, 1950-1970 (Box Series I-19)
  - Monna, A. F., 1966-1968 (Box Series I-19)
  - Monod, Jacques, 1965-1966 (Box Series I-19)
  - Montgomery, Deane, 1936-1955 (Box Series I-19)
    Soboconski, Boleslaw
  - Montroll, Elliot, 1966-1969 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mooers, Calvin N., 1957 (Box Series I-19)
  - Moore, Marion, 1975-1977 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morales, Manuel, 1976-1978; n.d. (Box Series I-19)
  - Moravesik, Michael J., 1956 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morgan, John C., 1972 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morgenstern, Carl (Box Series I-19)
    - Folder #1, 1968-1977 (Box Series I-19)
      Mathematical biology
    - Folder #2, n.d. (Box Series I-19)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar (Box Series I-19)
    - Folder #1, 1947-1960 (Box Series I-19)
      Some in German, JVN
    - Folder #2, 1963-1977 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morin, M. R., 1979 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morris, Scot, 1980-1981 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morrison, Donald R., 1981 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morrison, Edward J., 1970 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morrison, Philip, 1977 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morrissey, Richard H., 1975 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morse, A[nthony] P., 1958 (Box Series I-19)
    -See also Ser.I, Agnew, Ralph P.
  - Morse, Marston, 1936-1972; n.d. (Box Series I-19)
  - Morse, Philip M., 1956-1958 (Box Series I-19)
  - Morse, Richard, 1972-1978 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mosbacher, C. J., 1963 (Box Series I-19)
    Pergamon Press
  - Moses, Ray [C.], Jr., 1967, n.d. (Box Series I-19)
    Thermonuclear explosions
  - Moss, Norman, 1966 (Box Series I-19)
    Development of H-bomb
  - Mosteller, Frederick, 1967 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mostowski, A., 1958-1959;n.d. (Box Series I-19)
  - Motchane, L., 1979 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mott, Thomas E., 1961 (Box Series I-19)
    -See also Series XV
  - Mozzochi, C. J., 1978 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mrozowski, Stanislaw, 1955-1956 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mucks, Arlie M., 1978 (Box Series I-19)
  - Müldner, Tomasz, 1976 (Box Series I-19)
  - Muller, Mathieuz, 1973 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mulliken, Robert S., 1972-1975 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mullin, A. A., 1958 (Box Series I-19)
  - Munk, Walter, 1965 (Box Series I-19)
  - Munkres, Jim, 1953-1956 (Box Series I-19)
  - Musès, C., 1979 (Box Series I-19)
  - Muskie, Edmund S., 1967 (Box Series I-19)
    U.S. senators
    Baker, Howard H., Jr.
  - Mycielski, Jan (Box Series I-19)
    - Folder #1, 1958-1969 (Box Series I-19)
      BenDaniel, David J. (1980)
      Bishop, [?]
      [Condon?], Edward (1977)
      Mycielski, Emilia
      Tarski, Alfred (1977)
      -See also Ser.I, Kuratowski, Kazimierz
      -See also Ser.I, Wyman, Jeffries
    - Folder #2, 1970-1972 (Box Series I-19)
    - Folder #3, 1973-1975 (Box Series I-19)
    - Folder #4, 1976-1977 (Box Series I-19)
    - Folder #5, 1978-1984 (Box Series I-19)
    - Folder #6, n.d. (Box Series I-19)
  - Myers, Gerald, 1974 (Box Series I-19)
  - Myhre, Philip C., 1977 (Box Series I-19)
  - Mysels, K. J., 1981 (Box Series I-19)
  - Nadler, Sam B., Jr., 1974 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nagarajan, V., 1966 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nagy, John V., 1967 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nakano, Kazumi, 1979 (Box Series I-20)
  - Napier, Eleanor, 1958 (Box Series I-20)
  - Narasimhan, T. N., 1981 (Box Series I-20)
  - Narici, Lawrence, 1983 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nathanson, Melvyn B., 1976 (Box Series I-20)
  - National Science Foundation, 1966-1969 (Box Series I-20)
    Gaeta, Federico
    Mayer, J. Richard
  - Nauenberg, Michael, 1979 (Box Series I-20)
  - Neeley, Charles, 1974 (Box Series I-20)
    SMU number series
  - Neighbor, Ed, 1959-1961 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nelson, David, 1962; n.d. (Box Series I-20)
  - Nelson, E. L., 1947 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nemo, John, 1982 (Box Series I-20)
  - Neugebauer, O., 1937-1942 (Box Series I-20)
    Tamarkin, J. D.
  - Neuman, Bernard, 1972-1977 (Box Series I-20)
  - Neuman, Michael, 1971 (Box Series I-20)
  - Neumann, B. H., 1968 (Box Series I-20)
  - Neureiter, Norman P., 1967 (Box Series I-20)
  - Neuwirth, Lee P., 1972-1973 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nevin, Alice, n.d. (Box Series I-20)
  - Newgard, John J., 1959-1960 (Box Series I-20)
  - Newman, D. J. (Box Series I-20)
    -See Ser.I, Klamkin, M. S.
  - Newman, Donald, 1973 (Box Series I-20)
  - Newman, James R., 1958-1966 (Box Series I-20)
  - Newton, Quigg, 1961 (Box Series I-20)
  - Neyman, J. (Box Series I-20)
    - Folder #1, 1942-1971 (Box Series I-20)
    - Folder #2, 1972 (Box Series I-20)
    - Folder #3, 1973 (Box Series I-20)
    - Folder #4, n.d. (Box Series I-20)
  - Nicholas, Warren, 1978 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nichols, Basil, 1981 (Box Series I-20)
    -See also Ser.I Sobczyk, Andrew
  - Nilsson, Nils J., 1966 (Box Series I-20)
  - [Nirewoz?], Louis, 1969 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nishihara, Katsunobu, 1976 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nitecki, Zbigniew, 1982 (Box Series I-20)
    Polish mathematicians
  - Nivat, M[ario?], 1974 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nock, Arthur D., 1943 (Box Series I-20)
  - Norris, Eugene M., 1974-1979 (Box Series I-20)
  - Norton, Karl K., 1968-1976 (Box Series I-20)
    Briggs, William E.
  - Nosanow, L[ew] H., 1973 (Box Series I-20)
  - Novak, Mike, 1967-1971 (Box Series I-20)
  - Novogrod, Nancy, 1981 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nowak, Amran, 1965-1977 (Box Series I-20)
    -See Ser.I, Kielszewski, Z.
  - Nowosad, Pedro, 1970 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nuckolls, John, 1982-1983 (Box Series I-20)
  - Nugent, Paul T., 1977 (Box Series I-20)
  - O'Connor, Tom (Box Series I-21)
    -SeeSer.I, Tuck, J. L.
  - O'Dette, Ralph E., 1958 (Box Series I-21)
  - Odier, Marc, 1975-1978 (Box Series I-21)
  - Oettinger, Anthony G., 1961 (Box Series I-21)
  - Ogilvy, C. Stanley, 1961 (Box Series I-21)
  - Ohlinger, L. A., 1951 (Box Series I-21)
  - O'Keefe, John A., 1969-1977 (Box Series I-21)
  - O'Keefe, R. L, 1957 (Box Series I-21)
  - Olbert, Stanislaw, 1956 (Box Series I-21)
    Kellogg, J. M. B.
  - Olech, Czeslaw, 1973-1978; n.d. (Box Series I-21)
    Bartoszynski, Robert
  - Olesko, Lawrence A., 1967 (Box Series I-21)
  - Olive, William M., 1958 (Box Series I-21)
    re: cousin Julian Ulam
  - Oliver, Robert M., 1957-1960 (Box Series I-21)
    Cohen, Leon
  - O'Malley, Lawrence V., n.d. (Box Series I-21)
  - Ophir, Dan, 1974-1981 (Box Series I-21)
    -See also Ser.I, Godlewski-Ophir, J.
  - Opler, Ascher, 1957-1958 (Box Series I-21)
  - Oppenheimer, Frank, 1971 (Box Series I-21)
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1943-1963 (Box Series I-21)
    Restriction of info. at LASL
    Smith, Ralph Carlisle
  - Ore, Oystein, 1941 (Box Series I-21)
  - O'Rourke, N. W., 1957-1959 (Box Series I-21)
  - Orszag, Steven A., 1974 (Box Series I-21)
  - Orton, Dwayne, 1957 (Box Series I-21)
  - O'Sam-U, Hino, 1978 (Box Series I-21)
    Gamow & Math., 1976
  - Osgood, Thomas H., 1956-1957 (Box Series I-21)
  - Osland, Christopher Desmond, 1969; n.d. (Box Series I-21)
  - Ostrowski, Janusz, 1971 (Box Series I-21)
    Some in Polish, bio. of A. B. Dobrowolski
  - Oxtoby, John C. (Box Series I-21)
    - Folder #1, 1940-1945 (Box Series I-21)
      JVN, Erdös; measure in groups
    - Folder #2, 1946-1976 (Box Series I-21)
      Mazur-Banach game and Banach category theorem
    - Folder #3, n.d. (Box Series I-21)
    - Folder #4, 1938-1949 (Box Series I-21)
      1995-38ms; photo
    - Folder #5, 1957-1984 (Box Series I-21)
      1995-38ms
      Mauldin, Daniel
  - Padovana, Giorgio, 1968 (Box Series I-21)
  - Page, Ralph E., 1959 (Box Series I-21)
  - Palacios, Julio, 1959 (Box Series I-21)
  - Pallaschke, D. (Box Series I-21)
    Karpinski, M., 1980
  - Palmer, C. Harvey, 1940 (Box Series I-21)
  - Panepinto, Nicolo, 1981 (Box Series I-21)
  - Parcinski, Henry J., 1967-1968 (Box Series I-21)
  - Pardee, Arthur B., 1960-1961 (Box Series I-21)
  - Pareja, Diego, 1977-1980 (Box Series I-21)
  - Parikh, Jitendra C., 1978 (Box Series I-21)
  - Parks, Paul F., 1976-1977 (Box Series I-21)
  - Parmenter, Robert H., 1979 (Box Series I-21)
  - Parnes, Henry, 1966 (Box Series I-21)
  - Parodi, H., 1967 (Box Series I-21)
    prime numbers
  - Parter, Seymour V., 1982 (Box Series I-21)
  - Pasquino, Luisa Pece, 1978 (Box Series I-21)
  - Pasta, John, 1954-1974 (Box Series I-21)
    enclosures to 29 May 1956 in oversize; JVN
    Kolstad, George A.
    See Wendel, James G.
  - Paternoster, Dixie L., 1979 (Box Series I-21)
  - Paternoster, Richard, 1980 (Box Series I-21)
    Neutron transport problems
  - Patraw, ?, n.d. (Box Series I-21)
  - Patterson, David, 1976 (Box Series I-21)
  - Paxson, E. W., 1947 (Box Series I-21)
    RAND
  - Peale, Mundy I, 1961 (Box Series I-21)
  - Pearl, Judea, 1980-1982 (Box Series I-21)
  - Peaslee, Alfred T., 1954-1956 (Box Series I-21)
    Harvard Soc. of Fellows
    Shattuck, Henry L.
  - Peck, Leslie G., 1958 (Box Series I-21)
    Navy research, JVN
  - Pedoe, Dan, 1937-1976 (Box Series I-21)
  - Pekeris, C. L., 1959-1961 (Box Series I-21)
    Weizmann Inst. of Science; WEIZAC
  - Peierls, R. E., 1965 (Box Series I-21)
    BBC hist. of atom and H-bomb
    Bethe, Hans
  - Pell, William, 1970 (Box Series I-21)
  - Penguin Books LTD, 1970 (Box Series I-21)
    Sykes, Elizabeth
  - Penney, W. G., 1962-1964 (Box Series I-21)
    JVN
  - Pepinsky, Ray, 1966 (Box Series I-22)
    Nova Univ.
  - Peres, J., 1954 (Box Series I-22)
  - Pergamon Press, Inc. (Box Series I-22)
    - Folder #1, 1957-1959 (Box Series I-22)
      Dews, Edmund
      Flower, Joan
      Hutt, C. M.
      Kruskal, Martin
      Maxwell, I. R.
      Millar, Elaine C. P.
      Nadler, Morton
      Paolillo, Jeanne
      Stratford-Lawrence, Sylvia
    - Folder #2, 1959 (Box Series I-22)
    - Folder #3, 1960 (Box Series I-22)
  - Perlman, Mrs. Selig, 1964 (Box Series I-22)
  - Perlmutter, Arnold, 1971-1972 (Box Series I-22)
  - Perlmutter, Paul Q., 1979-1980 (Box Series I-22)
    Colorado College
  - Peter, James V., 1981 (Box Series I-22)
    Ham sandwich theorem
  - Peters, Max, 1967-1970 (Box Series I-22)
    National Medal of Science
    See Hawkins, David
  - Petersen, Karl, 1977 (Box Series I-22)
    Ergodic theorem
  - Peterson, A. W., 1942 (Box Series I-22)
  - Pettit, J. [I?], 1973 (Box Series I-22)
    1st day issue of sciences commemorative stamp
  - Philip, Miklos, 1972 (Box Series I-22)
    JVN in Hungary
  - Physical Society of Japan, 1973 (Box Series I-22)
    Ono, S.
  - Physics Today, 1958-1967 (Box Series I-22)
    Ellis, R. Hobart, Jr.
    Davis, Robert R.
  - Piel, Gerard, 1967-1981 (Box Series I-22)
    Scientific American
  - Pimbley, George H., 1973-1982 (Box Series I-22)
    See Bazley, Norman W.
  - Pinker, Aron, 1981 (Box Series I-22)
  - Piore, Emanuel R., 1957-1971 (Box Series I-22)
  - Pipes, Irene E., 1977 (Box Series I-22)
  - Piskorek, Adam, 1978 (Box Series I-22)
    Bialynicki-Birula, A.
  - Piszek, Edward J., 1973 (Box Series I-22)
  - Pitzer, K. S., 1961 (Box Series I-22)
    AEC E. O. Lawrence Award
    Rosen, Louis
    Taylor, Theodore
  - [Pivor?], Malcolm, 1973 (Box Series I-22)
    infinite sets
  - Plam-Meiman, Olga, 1977 (Box Series I-22)
    Meiman, Nohim
  - Pleszczynska, Joanna, 1982-1983 (Box Series I-22)
  - Polish American Congress, Inc., 1970-1971 (Box Series I-22)
    Heritage Award
    Kobelinski, Mitchell P.
    Rozanski, Edward C.
  - Pollard, Harry, 1966 (Box Series I-22)
  - Polya, George, 1957-1976 (Box Series I-22)
  - Pomerantz, ?, 1976 (Box Series I-22)
  - Poole, George, 1971 (Box Series I-22)
  - Porte, Jean, 1978 (Box Series I-22)
  - Porter, W[illiam] S., 1969 (Box Series I-22)
  - Posvar, Wesley W., 1978 (Box Series I-22)
    Univ. of Pitt. honorary degree
  - Potter, Allen, 1952 (Box Series I-22)
  - Powers, Thomas, 1981 (Box Series I-22)
    national defense
  - Frederick A. Praeger, Inc., 1968-1983 (Box Series I-22)
  - Prager, William, 1967 (Box Series I-22)
  - Preece, Warren E., 1968 (Box Series I-22)
    Math. & Logic
  - Prenowitz, Walter, 1958 (Box Series I-22)
    Lecture tour
  - Press, Frank, 1979-1981 (Box Series I-22)
    SALT Treaty; See Seitz, Frederick, scientists in Poland
  - Prewitt, Judith M. S., 1980 (Box Series I-22)
    Graph-to-graph comparison
  - Price, G. Baley, 1957-1958 (Box Series I-22)
    Bulletin of the AMS; JVN
  - Price, Peter J., 1975 (Box Series I-22)
    Applications of Monte Carlo; H-bomb calc.
  - Prigogine, I., 1978 (Box Series I-22)
    Nonequilibrium thermodynamics
  - Prim, R. C. (Box Series I-22)
  - Pritchard, William C., 1956-1966 (Box Series I-22)
  - Puck, Stirling M., 1965 (Box Series I-22)
  - Puck, Theodore (Box Series I-22)
    - Folder #1, 1958-1972 (Box Series I-22)
      Biophysics; grad. program at Univ. of Col. School of Medicine
      See Seaborg, Glenn
    - Folder #2, 1974-1981 (Box Series I-22)
    - Folder #3, n.d. (Box Series I-22)
  - Puslowski, Francis, 1981 (Box Series I-22)
  - Queneau, Raymond, 1968-1982 (Box Series I-22)
    Some in French; combinatorial analysis
  - Quesada, E. R. (Box Series I-22)
    See LeBaron, Robert
  - Rabi, I. I., 1957-1976 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rabinowitz, Steven, 1979 (Box Series I-23)
  - Raczka, [?], 1971 (Box Series I-23)
  - Raiffa, Howard, 1966 (Box Series I-23)
  - Ramakrishnan, Alladi, 1977 (Box Series I-23)
  - Ramberg, Walter, 1968 (Box Series I-23)
    J. Mycielski
  - Ramer, Roald, 1972 (Box Series I-23)
  - Ramey, James T., 1958-1966 (Box Series I-23)
    Outer space propulsion;Joint Commt. on Atomic Energy;LASL housing-bathtub row
    See Schreiber, Raemer
  - Ramsay, Arlan, 1973 (Box Series I-23)
  - Ramsay, Dwight M., 1957 (Box Series I-23)
    LASL salaries
  - Ramsey, Hal H., 1968 (Box Series I-23)
  - Randic, Milan, 1976 (Box Series I-23)
    Reconstruction of graphs
  - Rankin, Bayard, 1972 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rapp, George, 1978 (Box Series I-23)
  - Ras, Zbigniew, 1980 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rasiowa, Helena, 1977-1978 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rassias, George M (Box Series I-23)
    See Rassias, Themistocles M.
  - Rassias, Themistocles M., 1977-1983 (Box Series I-23)
    Non-linear analysis; Einstein vol.
    Rassias, George M.
  - Rathjens, George W., 1970 (Box Series I-23)
    Military tech. & arms control
  - Rathans, Rudolf, 1966-1967 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rautenstraus, R. C., 1977 (Box Series I-23)
    Gamow
  - Raymond, Detlev J., 1962-1966 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rebbi, Claudio, 1983 (Box Series I-23)
    random walk of particles
  - Redman, Helen F., 1957 (Box Series I-23)
  - Redman, Leslie M., 1957-1982 (Box Series I-23)
    Fermi LASL pubs.
  - Reed, Bill, 1977 (Box Series I-23)
  - Reed, Coke S., 1979 (Box Series I-23)
  - Reeve, E. B[asil], 1966 (Box Series I-23)
    biomathematics
  - Rechard, Ottis W., 1956-1961 (Box Series I-23)
    Hacker, Sidney G.
    Hershner, Iran R.
  - Regan, Bill, 1967 (Box Series I-23)
  - Regis College, 1973 (Box Series I-23)
  - Reichbach, Juliusz, 1966-1974 (Box Series I-23)
  - Reid, Justin T., 1950 (Box Series I-23)
    Chess
  - Reid, Walter P., 1956 (Box Series I-23)
  - Reines, Frederick, 1968-1980 (Box Series I-23)
    Gamow vol.
  - Reingold, Heim, 1976 (Box Series I-23)
  - Reinhardt, William N., 1970-1973 (Box Series I-23)
    Continuum hypothesis
  - Reitan, Paul H., 1977 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Inst., 1971 (Box Series I-23)
  - Reuz, Peter L., 1976-1977 (Box Series I-23)
  - Research Reports, n.d. (Box Series I-23)
    Eakins, Rosemary
  - Reynolds, Mark, 1982 (Box Series I-23)
    Tree of Math.
  - Rhodes, Richard, 1983 (Box Series I-23)
    Making of the Atomic Bomb
  - Rich, Alexander, 1960 (Box Series I-23)
  - Richards, C., 1971 (Box Series I-23)
  - Richardson, ?, 1936 (Box Series I-23)
    Election to AMS
  - Richardson, Oliver A., 1969 (Box Series I-23)
  - Richtmyer, Jane, 1968-1971 (Box Series I-23)
  - Richtmyer, R. D., 1947-1980;n.d. (Box Series I-23)
    Fissionable material explosions;Monte Carlo; hydrodynamics
    See also Series XV
  - Riecken, Henry W., 1959 (Box Series I-23)
  - Ripa, Karol, 1942 (Box Series I-23)
  - Rittenberg, David (Box Series I-23)
  - Roark, Howard D., 1969-1971 (Box Series I-24)
    Lundegard, Robert J.
  - Robb, John D., 1958 (Box Series I-24)
    Trial brief re: uranium & thorium
  - Robbin, Joel W., 1973 (Box Series I-24)
  - Robbins, Herbert E., 1943-1973 (Box Series I-24)
    Riemann integral, work on theorems
  - Roberts, Seth, 1978 (Box Series I-24)
  - Roberts, Walter Orr, 1961-1970 (Box Series I-24)
  - Robinson, Arthur, 1971 (Box Series I-24)
  - Robinson, D. W., 1958 (Box Series I-24)
  - Robinson, E. S., 1960 (Box Series I-24)
    Hapgood, Charles H.
  - Robinson, G. Stanislaw, n.d. (Box Series I-24)
  - Robinson, Julia, 1976 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rochester, Nathaniel, 1958 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rockoff, Maxine L., 1972 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rocky Mountain Journal of Mathematics, 1970-1971 (Box Series I-24)
    Scott, William
  - Rodgers, E. D., 1958-1961 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rodin, Ervin Y., 1973-1979 (Box Series I-24)
  - Roeling, Lloyd G., 1970 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rogers, David J., 1970 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rogers, J. D., 1959 (Box Series I-24)
    Plowshare
  - Rogers, Lorene L., 1975 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rogers, Tom, 1982 (Box Series I-24)
  - Roinestad, Lucille D., 1973 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rosen, Kenneth, 1973-1982 (Box Series I-24)
    U-numbers
  - Rosen, Walter B., n.d. (Box Series I-24)
  - Rosenberg, Samuel, 1970-1974 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rosenblith, Walter A., 1976 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rosenfeld, A. H., 1965 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rosenkrantz, Jens G., 1967 (Box Series I-24)
    Physiology
  - Rosenstiehl, P. (Box Series I-24)
  - Rosentiel, Mrs. Lewis, 1973 (Box Series I-24)
  - Ross, Arnold, 1961;n.d. (Box Series I-24)
    Quadratic iterations
  - Ross, Kenneth A., 1980 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rosser, J. Barkley (Box Series I-24)
    - Folder #1, 1960-1980 (Box Series I-24)
    - Folder #2, n.d. (Box Series I-24)
  - Rossolimo, Nicolas, 1959 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rost, Ernest, 1971 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rostafinski, W[ojcieah?], 1976 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rota, Gian-Carlo (Box Series I-24)
    - Folder #1, 1963-1967 (Box Series I-24)
      Vitae
    - Folder #2, 1968-1972 (Box Series I-24)
    - Folder #3, 1973-1984 (Box Series I-24)
      Review of Adv. of a Mathematician
    - Folder #4, n.d. (Box Series I-24)
  - Rotenberg, Manuel, 1960 (Box Series I-24)
  - Roth, Paul J., 1956 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rothschild, Bruce, 1980 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rothstein, Jerome, 1966 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rousch, Donald C., 1973 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rousseau, C. C., 1972-1978 (Box Series I-24)
  - Row, Peterson & Co., 1954-1955 (Box Series I-24)
    McPherson, Donald A.
    Oppegaard, Harry E.
  - Rowan, Julian, 1969 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rozanski, Edward L., 1970 (Box Series I-24)
  - Rozenberg, Grzegorz, 1974-1975 (Box Series I-24)